<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
	<rss version="2.0"
		xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"
		xmlns:wfw="http://wellformedweb.org/CommentAPI/"
		xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
		xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"

			>

	<channel>

		<title>[Resolved] App rejected &#8211; Politepix</title>
		<atom:link href="/forums/topic/app-rejected/feed/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
		<link>/forums/topic/app-rejected/feed/</link>
		<description></description>
		<lastBuildDate>Tue, 23 Apr 2024 14:58:07 +0000</lastBuildDate>
		<generator>https://bbpress.org/?v=2.6.9</generator>
		<language>en-US</language>

		
														
					
				<item>
					<guid>/forums/topic/app-rejected/#post-1018871</guid>
					<title><![CDATA[[Resolved] App rejected]]></title>
					<link>/forums/topic/app-rejected/#post-1018871</link>
					<pubDate>Tue, 12 Nov 2013 11:18:35 +0000</pubDate>
					<dc:creator>pablowaa</dc:creator>

					<description>
						<![CDATA[
						<p>Hi,</p>
<p>I&#8217;m using the OpenEars framework in one of my apps. It&#8217;s been recently rejected. The reason:</p>
<p>&#8220;During review we were prompted to provide consent to use the microphone, however, we were not able to find any features or functionality that use the microphone for audio recording.<br />
The microphone consent request is generated by the use of either AVAudioSessionCategoryRecord or AVAudioSessionCategoryPlayAndRecord audio categories.<br />
If you do not intend to record audio with your application, it would be appropriate to choose the AVAudioSession session category that fits your application&#8217;s needs or modify your app to include audio-recording features.&#8221;</p>
<p>Is there any way to fix it? The only part of the app where I&#8217;m using the microphone is where the OpenEars framework is being used.</p>
<p>Thank you</p>
						]]>
					</description>

					
					
				</item>

			
				<item>
					<guid>/forums/topic/app-rejected/#post-1018872</guid>
					<title><![CDATA[Reply To: App rejected]]></title>
					<link>/forums/topic/app-rejected/#post-1018872</link>
					<pubDate>Tue, 12 Nov 2013 11:44:54 +0000</pubDate>
					<dc:creator>Halle Winkler</dc:creator>

					<description>
						<![CDATA[
						<p>Welcome pablowaa,</p>
<p>I&#8217;m sorry you had an app rejection &#8212; this is the first time I&#8217;ve ever heard of one as a result of using the framework for a purpose it was designed for (I heard of one other temporary rejection back in 2011, but it was due to an obvious misuse of the framework). Are you doing speech recognition in your app or just TTS?</p>
						]]>
					</description>

					
					
				</item>

			
				<item>
					<guid>/forums/topic/app-rejected/#post-1018874</guid>
					<title><![CDATA[Reply To: App rejected]]></title>
					<link>/forums/topic/app-rejected/#post-1018874</link>
					<pubDate>Tue, 12 Nov 2013 12:00:52 +0000</pubDate>
					<dc:creator>pablowaa</dc:creator>

					<description>
						<![CDATA[
						<p>Hi, thanks for your response.</p>
<p>I&#8217;m doing speech recognition. Only recognise 2 words (&#8220;next&#8221;/&#8221;forward&#8221;) to navigate between slides in one section inside the app.</p>
<p>I&#8217;ll give you some more background about the app:<br />
This app is part of a family that has been using the OpenEars framework since iOS 5.   When I release a new app I change the content, themes, and I update the UI and code to work with the new iOS version requirements.<br />
The only place where I use the microphone is in OpenEars framework and Apple never reported a problem about it. This is the first time I release an app from this family for iOS 7, so I don&#8217;t know if it has something to do with iOS 7?</p>
<p>According to Apple I&#8217;m using audio recording, but the only thing I do is recognising 2 words with OpenEars</p>
						]]>
					</description>

					
					
				</item>

			
				<item>
					<guid>/forums/topic/app-rejected/#post-1018875</guid>
					<title><![CDATA[Reply To: App rejected]]></title>
					<link>/forums/topic/app-rejected/#post-1018875</link>
					<pubDate>Tue, 12 Nov 2013 12:45:20 +0000</pubDate>
					<dc:creator>Halle Winkler</dc:creator>

					<description>
						<![CDATA[
						<p>Correct, OpenEars uses the AVAudioSession PlayAndRecord, which is how it is able to use the mic input for speech recognition. If it didn&#8217;t use a recording audio session, no recognition would be possible because there would be no microphone access. It&#8217;s expected that any app making use of the mic for low-latency usage will have that kind of audio session.</p>
<p>Starting with iOS7, whenever the mic is first made live in the app, the user is asked permission for mic access. This is a very good thing in my opinion, especially for applications like speech recognition. Apple&#8217;s rejection is basically saying that you are getting this permission, but it isn&#8217;t clear to them what you are doing with it and they want any mic-using feature to be made apparent to new users of the app. I don&#8217;t know what your UI is like so I don&#8217;t know if this is an accurate critique or not; not every reviewer is the same and they have a lot to do and can occasionally overlook things like everyone else, but let&#8217;s operate on the assumption that it&#8217;s correct.</p>
<p>Solving this in a definitive way is an app implementation issue rather than a framework issue and is probably something more for the realm of visual UI than speech UI, which isn&#8217;t inside of the scope of things OpenEars tries to do (besides giving you hooks like the audio input volume so you can create a visual UI in your app). But since it is clearly a concern for Apple, which means it&#8217;s a concern of people using OpenEars, I will add a warning about the necessity of communicating the fact that the app is using the mic for speech recognition in the OpenEars documentation.</p>
<p>I can make some suggestions about how to indicate to the user that there is ongoing speech recognition. You could describe it via an introductory alert on first run, right before starting the speech recognition so that the permission request appears in the context of allowing speech recognition. Alternately you could probably indicate it with a label or an icon.</p>
<p>Since you have the rejection email, though, I would simply ask them directly. &#8220;My app is performing speech recognition by doing keyword spotting as part of its user interface, which is why the PlayAndRecord audio session is in use. Based on the rejection reason, this voice UI feature isn&#8217;t apparent. What would be the best way for me to indicate that my app has a voice UI to my users so that the features or functionality that use the microphone for audio recording are clearly apparent?&#8221;</p>
						]]>
					</description>

					
					
				</item>

			
				<item>
					<guid>/forums/topic/app-rejected/#post-1019207</guid>
					<title><![CDATA[Reply To: [Resolved] App rejected]]></title>
					<link>/forums/topic/app-rejected/#post-1019207</link>
					<pubDate>Thu, 19 Dec 2013 09:39:18 +0000</pubDate>
					<dc:creator>Halle Winkler</dc:creator>

					<description>
						<![CDATA[
						<p>I&#8217;m marking this resolved because although it isn&#8217;t possible for this project to handle the visual UI requirements or user education requirements of indicating microphone use, it provides hooks for easy UI building, and I&#8217;ve added a note about this requirement to the FAQ so everyone understands that Apple wants an indication of mic usage to be part of the interface of a mic-using app.</p>
						]]>
					</description>

					
					
				</item>

			
				<item>
					<guid>/forums/topic/app-rejected/#post-1019546</guid>
					<title><![CDATA[Reply To: [Resolved] App rejected]]></title>
					<link>/forums/topic/app-rejected/#post-1019546</link>
					<pubDate>Wed, 15 Jan 2014 23:10:18 +0000</pubDate>
					<dc:creator>SPatrickB</dc:creator>

					<description>
						<![CDATA[
						<p>My app update (for iOS 7) just got rejected for the exact same reason given by Apple. Trouble is my app is only using TTS and so should not use the microphone.<br />
If a flag could be set in the API for TTS only (use AVAudioSessionCategoryPlayback) then I think this could be resolved.</p>
						]]>
					</description>

					
					
				</item>

			
				<item>
					<guid>/forums/topic/app-rejected/#post-1019548</guid>
					<title><![CDATA[Reply To: [Resolved] App rejected]]></title>
					<link>/forums/topic/app-rejected/#post-1019548</link>
					<pubDate>Wed, 15 Jan 2014 23:14:35 +0000</pubDate>
					<dc:creator>Halle Winkler</dc:creator>

					<description>
						<![CDATA[
						<p>Welcome,</p>
<p>Sorry, that&#8217;s frustrating. You can set this behavior by setting the property noAudioSessionOverrides to TRUE in your FliteController. Please test that it gives the desired result of no audio session overrides on a new install of your app before re-submitting!</p>
						]]>
					</description>

					
					
				</item>

			
				<item>
					<guid>/forums/topic/app-rejected/#post-1019751</guid>
					<title><![CDATA[Reply To: [Resolved] App rejected]]></title>
					<link>/forums/topic/app-rejected/#post-1019751</link>
					<pubDate>Thu, 16 Jan 2014 11:00:15 +0000</pubDate>
					<dc:creator>Halle Winkler</dc:creator>

					<description>
						<![CDATA[
						<p>I&#8217;ve decided that the next version will do this automatically if you are doing TTS without speech recognition so this doesn&#8217;t affect anyone else. ETA for version 1.65 is in the next week or so.</p>
						]]>
					</description>

					
					
				</item>

			
				<item>
					<guid>/forums/topic/app-rejected/#post-1019752</guid>
					<title><![CDATA[Reply To: [Resolved] App rejected]]></title>
					<link>/forums/topic/app-rejected/#post-1019752</link>
					<pubDate>Thu, 16 Jan 2014 11:52:31 +0000</pubDate>
					<dc:creator>SPatrickB</dc:creator>

					<description>
						<![CDATA[
						<p>I set that flag but I still see an entry for my app appearing in settings/privacy/microphone. However, it&#8217;s OK, I&#8217;ll just wait out until the next version of OpenEars.</p>
						]]>
					</description>

					
					
				</item>

			
				<item>
					<guid>/forums/topic/app-rejected/#post-1019753</guid>
					<title><![CDATA[Reply To: [Resolved] App rejected]]></title>
					<link>/forums/topic/app-rejected/#post-1019753</link>
					<pubDate>Thu, 16 Jan 2014 11:57:59 +0000</pubDate>
					<dc:creator>Halle Winkler</dc:creator>

					<description>
						<![CDATA[
						<p>You would need to completely uninstall the app including its settings and let it reinstall as a new app, since that setting is made on the first install ever when you accept the permission request.</p>
						]]>
					</description>

					
					
				</item>

					
		
	</channel>
	</rss>

