<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
	<rss version="2.0"
		xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"
		xmlns:wfw="http://wellformedweb.org/CommentAPI/"
		xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
		xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"

			>

	<channel>

		<title>Recognition lag &#8211; Politepix</title>
		<atom:link href="/forums/topic/problems-with-version-2-0/feed/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
		<link>/forums/topic/problems-with-version-2-0/feed/</link>
		<description></description>
		<lastBuildDate>Tue, 23 Apr 2024 15:00:57 +0000</lastBuildDate>
		<generator>https://bbpress.org/?v=2.6.9</generator>
		<language>en-US</language>

		
														
					
				<item>
					<guid>/forums/topic/problems-with-version-2-0/#post-1023425</guid>
					<title><![CDATA[Recognition lag]]></title>
					<link>/forums/topic/problems-with-version-2-0/#post-1023425</link>
					<pubDate>Thu, 11 Dec 2014 18:21:56 +0000</pubDate>
					<dc:creator>nrbrook</dc:creator>

					<description>
						<![CDATA[
						<p>I&#8217;ve upgraded to 2.0 in a new branch so I can easily switch between versions.  I haven&#8217;t changed any implementation details other than those required to support the API changes.  I&#8217;m having a number of problems which could all be related, they are hard to pin down.  Here&#8217;s one problem I keep getting:</p>
<blockquote><p>An utterance appears to be stuck in listening mode. Exiting stuck utterance.</p></blockquote>
<p>Before this is logged speech recognition hangs for quite a few seconds.</p>
						]]>
					</description>

					
					
				</item>

			
				<item>
					<guid>/forums/topic/problems-with-version-2-0/#post-1023428</guid>
					<title><![CDATA[Reply To: Recognition lag]]></title>
					<link>/forums/topic/problems-with-version-2-0/#post-1023428</link>
					<pubDate>Thu, 11 Dec 2014 18:36:48 +0000</pubDate>
					<dc:creator>Halle Winkler</dc:creator>

					<description>
						<![CDATA[
						<p>Slow recognitions have been reported a couple of times and both times it was due to not all the steps in the upgrade guide having been completed.</p>
						]]>
					</description>

					
					
				</item>

			
				<item>
					<guid>/forums/topic/problems-with-version-2-0/#post-1023429</guid>
					<title><![CDATA[Reply To: Recognition lag]]></title>
					<link>/forums/topic/problems-with-version-2-0/#post-1023429</link>
					<pubDate>Thu, 11 Dec 2014 18:39:18 +0000</pubDate>
					<dc:creator>nrbrook</dc:creator>

					<description>
						<![CDATA[
						<p>Which steps?  I have followed all the steps and apart from step 1, step 2 and step 5 the project would not compile if I had not made the changes successfully</p>
						]]>
					</description>

					
					
				</item>

			
				<item>
					<guid>/forums/topic/problems-with-version-2-0/#post-1023430</guid>
					<title><![CDATA[Reply To: Recognition lag]]></title>
					<link>/forums/topic/problems-with-version-2-0/#post-1023430</link>
					<pubDate>Thu, 11 Dec 2014 18:44:57 +0000</pubDate>
					<dc:creator>Halle Winkler</dc:creator>

					<description>
						<![CDATA[
						<p>For this issue, my best guess would be that your app is still linking to the old acoustic models. As you mentioned, there are a lot of steps that won&#8217;t lead to compilation errors if you skip them, so it has to be done pretty carefully.</p>
						]]>
					</description>

					
					
				</item>

			
				<item>
					<guid>/forums/topic/problems-with-version-2-0/#post-1023431</guid>
					<title><![CDATA[Reply To: Recognition lag]]></title>
					<link>/forums/topic/problems-with-version-2-0/#post-1023431</link>
					<pubDate>Thu, 11 Dec 2014 18:50:56 +0000</pubDate>
					<dc:creator>nrbrook</dc:creator>

					<description>
						<![CDATA[
						<p>I replaced them again with the versions from the archive, I&#8217;m still getting the message 25 seconds after I start listening, every time.</p>
<p>Step 1 and 2 are replacing the bundles and frameworks.  I&#8217;ve definitely done this.</p>
<p>Step 5 is architectural changes.  The pocketsphinx usage I have changed, I&#8217;m not generating a language model.  I am using OEEventsObserver correctly.</p>
<p>Thanks</p>
						]]>
					</description>

					
					
				</item>

			
				<item>
					<guid>/forums/topic/problems-with-version-2-0/#post-1023432</guid>
					<title><![CDATA[Reply To: Recognition lag]]></title>
					<link>/forums/topic/problems-with-version-2-0/#post-1023432</link>
					<pubDate>Thu, 11 Dec 2014 19:05:55 +0000</pubDate>
					<dc:creator>Halle Winkler</dc:creator>

					<description>
						<![CDATA[
						<p>If you can replicate it with isolated changes to the sample app I can take a look at it. There&#8217;s no known bug which does this, so without any logging info or device/version info or code to run I don&#8217;t have a way of helping out. </p>
<p>As I mentioned in the other thread, Rejecto is not designed to create language models for import without Rejecto running in the app, so that should be fixed in order to remove it as a potential issue, and I would be concerned about the switching branches back and forth thing since 2.0 isn&#8217;t just an API change but also changes in assets. That ought to work fine in theory, but it sounds like a source of debugging complexity right now.</p>
<p>I think that if I was seeing weird behavior like this, my steps would be as follows:</p>
<p>1. Use Rejecto as designed or use an OELanguageModelGenerator to create your LM if you aren&#8217;t using Rejecto,<br />
2. Attempt to replicate in the sample app using the smallest-possible changes, and<br />
3. If it doesn&#8217;t replicate, compare the two apps to see what&#8217;s different, and if it replicates, share the minimal code alterations and device and iOS version that causes it to replicate with the sample app with me.</p>
						]]>
					</description>

					
					
				</item>

			
				<item>
					<guid>/forums/topic/problems-with-version-2-0/#post-1023444</guid>
					<title><![CDATA[Reply To: Recognition lag]]></title>
					<link>/forums/topic/problems-with-version-2-0/#post-1023444</link>
					<pubDate>Thu, 11 Dec 2014 19:55:02 +0000</pubDate>
					<dc:creator>nrbrook</dc:creator>

					<description>
						<![CDATA[
						<p>I have a sample App which exhibits the problem, where should I send it?</p>
						]]>
					</description>

					
					
				</item>

			
				<item>
					<guid>/forums/topic/problems-with-version-2-0/#post-1023445</guid>
					<title><![CDATA[Reply To: Recognition lag]]></title>
					<link>/forums/topic/problems-with-version-2-0/#post-1023445</link>
					<pubDate>Thu, 11 Dec 2014 19:56:31 +0000</pubDate>
					<dc:creator>Halle Winkler</dc:creator>

					<description>
						<![CDATA[
						<p>Great. I only want the changed lines, not the entire app, but you can send them to the email address that you received your framework license email from.</p>
						]]>
					</description>

					
					
				</item>

			
				<item>
					<guid>/forums/topic/problems-with-version-2-0/#post-1023446</guid>
					<title><![CDATA[Reply To: Recognition lag]]></title>
					<link>/forums/topic/problems-with-version-2-0/#post-1023446</link>
					<pubDate>Thu, 11 Dec 2014 19:59:45 +0000</pubDate>
					<dc:creator>Halle Winkler</dc:creator>

					<description>
						<![CDATA[
						<p>Remember to also send me your device and iOS version where this replicates, thanks!</p>
						]]>
					</description>

					
					
				</item>

			
				<item>
					<guid>/forums/topic/problems-with-version-2-0/#post-1023485</guid>
					<title><![CDATA[Reply To: Recognition lag]]></title>
					<link>/forums/topic/problems-with-version-2-0/#post-1023485</link>
					<pubDate>Thu, 11 Dec 2014 22:38:02 +0000</pubDate>
					<dc:creator>Halle Winkler</dc:creator>

					<description>
						<![CDATA[
						<p>OK, the issues I see in your sample app version is that the vadThreshold is too low to operate (I would leave it on the current default of 2.0), which is going to create oversensitivity in combination with your lowered secondsOfSilenceToDetect, and it is using Rejecto in an unsupported way (see above, and our previous discussion). If fixing those issues doesn&#8217;t improve the slow search, it&#8217;s fine to send me a sample app version which uses Rejecto to dynamically generate your LM to demonstrate the issue.</p>
						]]>
					</description>

					
					
				</item>

					
		
	</channel>
	</rss>

