<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss version="2.0"
	xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"
	xmlns:wfw="http://wellformedweb.org/CommentAPI/"
	xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
	xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"
	xmlns:sy="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/syndication/"
	xmlns:slash="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/slash/"
	
	xmlns:georss="http://www.georss.org/georss"
	xmlns:geo="http://www.w3.org/2003/01/geo/wgs84_pos#"
	>

<channel>
	<title>openears &#8211; Politepix</title>
	<atom:link href="/tag/openears-2/feed/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
	<link>/</link>
	<description>iOS Frameworks for speech recognition, text to speech and more</description>
	<lastBuildDate>Thu, 25 Oct 2012 14:15:01 +0000</lastBuildDate>
	<language>en-US</language>
	<sy:updatePeriod>
	hourly	</sy:updatePeriod>
	<sy:updateFrequency>
	1	</sy:updateFrequency>
	<generator>https://wordpress.org/?v=6.5.2</generator>
<site xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">206848719</site>	<item>
		<title>OpenEars 1.2.1, RapidEars 1.1, Rejecto 1.0</title>
		<link>/2012/09/20/openears-1-2-1-rapidears-1-1-rejecto-1-0/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Halle Winkler]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Thu, 20 Sep 2012 20:59:22 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Code]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[frameworks]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[openears]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[plugins]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[rapidears]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[rejecto]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[xcode]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">/?p=11204</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Another big release day! OpenEars 1.2.1 is out, adding the very-suddenly-required armv7s slice and fixing the bug in which speech from right before a call to suspendRecognition will be processed after recognition is resumed. Downloadable at /openears. Also released today is RapidEars 1.1, which further refines many improvements of the past few versions and is [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Another big release day! <a href="/openears">OpenEars 1.2.1</a> is out, adding the very-suddenly-required armv7s slice and fixing the bug in which speech from right before a call to suspendRecognition will be processed after recognition is resumed. Downloadable at <a href="/openears">/openears</a>. Also released today is <a href="/rapidears">RapidEars 1.1</a>, which further refines many improvements of the past few versions and is stable, fast, resource-frugal and behaves better when changing language models and when suspending/resuming. You can read more about it and try out the demo at <a href="/rapidears">/rapidears</a>. If you&#8217;ve tried an earlier version, <a href="/rapidears">RapidEars 1.1</a> is really worth a second look.</p>
<p>[politepix-blog-inline-text-ad]</p>
<p>Politepix has also released a new paid plugin called <a href="/rejecto">Rejecto</a>, which makes your apps more accurate when you use OpenEars and RapidEars by tuning out words that aren&#8217;t in your language model. As usual it&#8217;s easy to get started with but it has a lot of knobs to twiddle if you want to optimize your model as far as possible. Check it out at <a href="/rejecto">/rejecto</a>.</p>
<p>While you&#8217;re trying these new tools out, why not make it easy on yourself and visit Politepix&#8217;s new <a href="/openears/tutorial">tutorial tool</a>, which will get you up and running with your OpenEars app about 5 minutes. It&#8217;s found at <a href="/openears/tutorial">/openears/tutorial</a> and it includes instructions for all the OpenEars classes and all of the plugins too!</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">11204</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>OpenEars 1.1, plugins, and RapidEars live recognition for iOS!</title>
		<link>/2012/06/18/openears-1-1-plugins-and-rapidears/</link>
					<comments>/2012/06/18/openears-1-1-plugins-and-rapidears/#comments</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Halle Winkler]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Mon, 18 Jun 2012 12:36:35 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Code]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[openears]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[plugin]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[rapidears]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[speech recognition]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">/?p=9839</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[OpenEars 1.1, the OpenEars plugin system, and RapidEars 1.0, a plugin for OpenEars for live recognition! Today is a big release day for Politepix: OpenEars 1.1 and the introduction of the OpenEars plugin system! Featuring RapidEars, a plugin for OpenEars that does recognition on live speech. I am very happy to be introducing multiple Cool [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<h1>OpenEars 1.1, the OpenEars plugin system, and RapidEars 1.0, a plugin for OpenEars for live recognition!</h1>
<h3>Today is a big release day for Politepix: OpenEars 1.1 and the introduction of the OpenEars plugin system! Featuring RapidEars, a plugin for OpenEars that does recognition on live speech.</h3>
<p>I am very happy to be introducing multiple <strong>Cool Things</strong> this Monday. The first is the <a href="/openears">1.1 version of OpenEars</a>, which was a bit behind schedule but I hope was worth waiting for, since it introduces&#8230;n-best! So you can now see the top &#8220;hits&#8221; for word matching and the scores for them, rather than only seeing the best hypothesis. You can just turn on n-best and set the number of best hypotheses you&#8217;d like in PocketsphinxController, and then add the n-best delegate method of OpenEarsEventsObserver to receive them wherever you&#8217;d like. The docs and sample app have been updated to explain how.</p>
<p>[politepix-blog-inline-text-ad]</p>
<p>The other big new feature of OpenEars 1.1 is that it now has a method that is entirely designed to make it easier for you to test, which is:</p>
<p>&#8211; (void) runRecognitionOnWavFileAtPath:(NSString *)wavPath usingLanguageModelAtPath:(NSString *)languageModelPath dictionaryAtPath:(NSString *)dictionaryPath languageModelIsJSGF:(BOOL)languageModelIsJSGF;</p>
<p>This just runs recognition using your normal settings on a single WAV audio file. You can use this to create a testbed in case, for instance, you are trying to see the effect that changes to a language model or acoustic model or other settings have on recognition. There&#8217;s more about both of these new features in the documentation and as always, feel free to ask your questions on the <a>forums</a>.</p>
<h3>The OpenEars Platform and Plugins</h3>
<p><a href="/rapidears"><img decoding="async" src="https://i0.wp.com/www.politepix.com/wp-content/uploads/rapidears_icon2.png?resize=150%2C150&#038;ssl=1" alt="" title="rapidears_icon" width="150" height="150" class="alignnone size-thumbnail wp-image-9852" data-recalc-dims="1" /></a><br />
The next big new thing is that OpenEars now has plugins. Over the coming months Politepix will be introducing new drop-in plugin frameworks for your OpenEars app that will open up new functionality. OpenEars will remain free and will also continue to be developed, with new features being added that make use of the potential of its dependencies, such as today&#8217;s introduction of n-best. For in-demand functionality that requires major committed development time and brand-new internal and dependency code, those features will be produced as plug-ins sold at the Politepix shop. So OpenEars is now both a free recognition, TTS and language modeling SDK, and also a platform so you can mix and match the exact extended functionality you need without making your app more complex.</p>
<p>Without further ado, it&#8217;s my pleasure to introduce Politepix&#8217;s first plugin for the OpenEars platform: <strong><a href="/rapidears">RapidEars</a></strong>! RapidEars is a plugin that adds live recognition capabilities to PocketsphinxController, so by trading off some accuracy, you can run recognition on speech as it is recorded into the device instead of waiting for a pause and evaluating afterwards. This uses more CPU than OpenEars so it&#8217;s advisable to use this for apps targeted at the newest devices. It&#8217;s great for games or any app where you want immediate responsiveness. There is nothing like this available using any other speech recognition product because they are all network-based and OpenEars is processed on the device. RapidEars is €999 to license and it has a free demo version for development that can be used for four minutes at a time so you can test it thoroughly before licensing. Installation is as simple as dragging the new plugin into your project and importing its classes in order to use new PocketsphinxController and OpenEarsEventsObserver methods.</p>
<p>You can read more about RapidEars <a href="/rapidears">here</a> and download a demo version of the plugin <a href="/shop/rapidearsdemo">here</a>. Questions for this OpenEars plugin and future ones can also be asked on the OpenEars forums, just mention that you&#8217;re asking about RapidEars.</p>
<p>That&#8217;s it, have fun with these new products!</p>
<p>-Halle</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>/2012/06/18/openears-1-1-plugins-and-rapidears/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>2</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">9839</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>OpenEars 1.0 released</title>
		<link>/2012/03/07/newopenearsrelease10/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Halle Winkler]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Wed, 07 Mar 2012 19:16:19 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Uncategorized]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[code]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[linkedin]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[openears]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[politepix]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">/?p=8737</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[I am extraordinarily happy to announce that OpenEars 1.0 is out now. This version has so many fixes and new features: Ultra-fast, ultra-easy install All-C language modelling and 3x faster phonetic lookup fallback method for vastly faster dynamic language model generation Language model generation is now tuned to creating contextual models from long sentences with [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>I am extraordinarily happy to announce that OpenEars 1.0 is <a href="/openears">out now</a>. This version has <strong>so</strong> many fixes and new features:</p>
<ul>
<li>Ultra-fast, ultra-easy install</li>
<li>All-C language modelling and 3x faster phonetic lookup fallback method for vastly faster dynamic language model generation</li>
<li>Language model generation is now tuned to creating contextual models from long sentences with improved recognition accuracy</li>
<li>Only runs with ios 4 and 5 since the only devices that need 3 can&#8217;t use OpenEars due to hardware shortcomings. This allows optimizations that make OpenEars faster.</li>
<li>ARC/LLVM compatible</li>
<li>General recognition accuracy is improved, recognition speed is much faster in release versions due to LLVM</li>
<li>Uses the latest .7 versions of all of the Sphinx libraries</li>
<li>Calibration takes half the time and is configurable as an OpenEarsConfig.h constant</li>
<li>Silence detection period is configurable programmatically</li>
<li>It should no longer be necessary to do anything special in order to use iOS media objects such as AVPlayer.</li>
<li>It is possible to set OpenEars to programmatically mix with background sounds such as iPod music, although this is not a default setting.</li>
<li>OpenEars no longer attempts to start Pocketsphinx on a device that has no audio input available</li>
<li>OpenEars now cleans dynamic language model arrays on input for problematic whitespace</li>
<li>JSGF now has better perception </li>
<li>Dynamic JSGF switching has been added</li>
<li>The AudioSessionManager is now only used internally, since it was the main cause of configuration difficulty for most developers. OpenEars now manages the audio session automagically. Don&#8217;t call AudioSessionManager directly any more, it&#8217;s no longer a developer-facing class of OpenEars.</li>
<li>All reported bugs fixed</li>
<li>OpenEars has a license change and is no longer EFF/OSI-defined OSS. It is free as in beer so we&#8217;ll start calling it shared source instead of open source. The big license changes paraphrased (please read the new license since you are agreeing to it when you use the framework): you can&#8217;t redistribute it as source, using it in something other than an app requires permission and special licensing, contribution terms are spelled out. Although this affects a miniscule number of developers that have used OpenEars so far, it&#8217;s a change, so if absolutely anyone wants to talk this over with me/ask more about it, I sincerely welcome you to get in touch via the contact page and I will answer and discuss any good-faith question.</li>
</ul>
<p>[politepix-blog-inline-text-ad]</p>
<p>I really hope that you enjoy this easier, faster and more flexible 1.0 version of OpenEars!</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">8737</post-id>	</item>
	</channel>
</rss>
